[roars]
[narrator] Strange beasts and monsters...
vast riches, hidden treasures...
evil haunts, uncharted frontiers...
the mysterious unknown.
The people who are captivated
by the magic in those words...
are called...
Hunters!
[theme music plays]
[Chairman] Huh?
One more!
[Gon grunts]
-[Gon chuckles]
-Hmm?
-Gotcha! You just used your right hand!
-I did.
[giggles] I did it! Yeah!
[Gon cheers]
[snoring gently]
SOLUTION x IS x MAJORITY x RULES
[narrator] As dawn breaks,
the airship carrying Gon and his friends
approaches its destination.
The Third Phase of the Hunter Exam
is about to begin.
-[snoring]
-[PA system tone]
[Beans] I sincerely apologize
for the long wait.
The airship will be arriving
at its destination shortly.
[Gon gasps]
[Gon] Is this where the next test
is gonna be held?
-[man 1] What is this place?
-[man 2] There's nothing here.
[Beans clears throat]
Everyone, this is the site
of the Hunter Exam's Third Phase.
You'll be competing here
at the top of the Trick Tower.
Did you say Trick Tower?
[Beans] In order to pass this phase,
you must reach the base
of the tower alive.
The time limit is 72 hours.
And with that,
the Exam's Third Phase will now begin.
-Good luck to each and every one of you.
-[crowd murmuring]
[Lippo snickering]
[Lippo] So, it's finally my turn, hey?
[Lippo chewing]
[Lippo snickering]
[Beans] All right, everyone. Do your best.
[grunts]
[Gon] Whoa!
Now what? Are we supposed to climb down?
Well, I hope not. That would be suicide.
[Number 86 chuckles] Sure, for most guys.
[grunts] For an expert rock climber
like me, this is gonna be a piece of cake.
Oh, wow!
Look at how fast he's going!
[chuckles] By the look of things,
I'm about to be the first one
to pass the Third Phase.
Huh?
[distant thudding]
-[creatures shrieking]
-[Number 86 gasps]
[screams]
No! Stop! Go away!
Help me!
Uh, so, I guess we can't climb down,
not this way at least.
Yeah.
-What's up?
-There are fewer people around.
What?
[Kurapika] I count 23.
So nearly half the applicants
have already found an exit.
No way! When did that happen?
We're missing something, but what is it?
There must be hidden doors
up here somewhere
that lead to the lower floors
of the tower.
Kurapika! Leorio!
What is it, Gon?
Look at this. We found a trap door.
Check it out!
[stone scraping]
[gasping]
I see, so the only way
that we can reach the lower levels
-is by turning over these stones.
-Okay, good job!
Now what do you say we head on down?
Okay, but I'm sort of confused.
Why? What is there to be confused about?
There's one, and another, and another,
and another one right over there.
There's a lot of them.
That many?
Five hidden doors
located in the same area.
Sounds a bit suspicious.
No doubt a few of them are traps.
From what I can tell, each of these
trap doors can only be used one time.
[Leorio] Seriously?
[Killua]
We saw somebody fall through one earlier,
but when we tried to open it,
it wouldn't budge an inch.
Judging by the door's size,
only one applicant can go through it
at a time.
Which means only one person
can use each door.
It's beginning to look like
we're all gonna have to split up.
We decided that we'll each pick a door,
and see how it goes.
And no hard feelings
if one of them's a trap.
How about you guys?
What are you gonna do?
Works for me. Seems like luck
is part of the game or something.
No objection here. That settles it.
[Leorio] On the count of three, we all
hop in at exactly the same time, okay?
[Gon] I guess that means
this is goodbye for now, guys.
We'll meet up at the base of the tower.
Let's do this. One...
-Two...
-[all] Three.
[Leorio yelps]
[all grunt]
[yelps and groans]
[groans] Huh?
[all gasp]
[Leorio] Wait, what?
[both chuckle]
-That was certainly a brief farewell.
-No kidding!
I don't think any of us expected
all those hidden doors
to lead us all to the same room.
Huh?
[Gon] Hey, look at this!
"The five who drop into this chamber
must find their way down together
by consensus of the majority.
Wait, five?
Look! They even left us five wrist timers.
[Killua] With buttons marked X and O.
Do you think it's possible that we won't
be able to leave this room at all
until someone else drops in
and joins us down here?
[Lippo over speaker] Very good!
Who's there?
[Lippo] My name is Lippo.
I'm the prison warden here,
not to mention, your examiner
for the Third Phase of the Exam.
Did he say prison warden?
We've gone to the trouble of preparing
multiple routes through the Tower,
and the one you've chosen
is the path of majority rule.
If you want to pass, and I'm sure you do,
co-operation is the essence of success.
One person acting selfishly could derail
the entire group.
And of course,
you won't be permitted to start
until you have five members present.
That's it, gentlemen. Best of luck!
[groans] We seriously can't start
until somebody else shows up?
-So, what now?
-[Kurapika] I guess we just have to wait.
[chair squeaks]
[whistles]
-[prisoner] You wanted to see us, Warden?
-The test begins now.
So go, take your positions!
[prisoners] Yes, sir.
[Leorio] Oh, come on!
We've been sitting here for two hours.
What if everybody else
already found their way down?
What are we supposed to do, huh?
We can't be the only ones stuck
at the top, we'll look like total idiots!
[Kurapika]
Calm down, Leorio. Complaining won't help.
Calm down? What if nobody else shows up
before we reach the end of our time limit?
Huh? [groans]
I can't just sit here--
-Shh! Be quiet.
-Huh?
Do you hear that sound?
[tapping]
[stone crumbling]
[Tonpa groans]
Wow! Good grief!
Mr. Tonpa!
-Oh, great.
-Look who it is.
Okay.
[rumbling]
I see.
So the door must be programmed to appear
once all five timers are put on.
[Gon] "At this door, select O to open,
X not to open."
Using majority rule, already? All right!
At least the answer is obvious.
[Leorio] What?
'Fess up! Which one of you jokers
hit the X button?
[chuckles] That was me. Sorry about that.
I guess I pressed the wrong button.
Stop screwing around, old man!
What, are you blind or something?
I said it was just an honest mistake.
How in the hell do you press
the wrong damn button, huh?
It doesn't matter. It's okay.
The door's open now.
[Leorio] It does matter!
He pressed the wrong button on purpose.
He's trying to sabotage us!
Let's go.
We don't have time for petty bickering.
Yeah, he's right.
Let him keep pressing the wrong button
if he wants to.
The rest of us will just have to press
the right one.
Fine, I guess.
[sneers] All right, let's go.
[Leorio grunts angrily]
[Leorio] Seriously? I didn't think
we'd get another question so soon.
[Gon] "Which way do you want to go?
O for right, X for left."
[Leorio] Right?
Or left?
[timers beep]
[groans] Hey!
Why would you wanna go right?
You always go left! What's wrong with you?
That's true.
As research has shown, people who are lost
or find themselves at a crossroads
tend to choose to go to the left
much more frequently than the right.
Y'know, I think I've heard that before.
Hold on a second.
The numbers just don't add up!
Which direction did the two of you pick?
-Right.
Ugh. You little monsters...
Going right makes a lot of sense.
The examiner will never see it coming.
If they've seen the same research
that those two have,
I bet they made the left path way harder.
[growls] Ugh!
Okay, so we're both simple-minded.
So what?
[Gon] "We?"
[Leorio gasps] Where the hell are we?
See that, over there?
[prisoner] The applicants are here.
Unlock my handcuffs.
Here we go.
There, now let's get down to business.
HUNTER GLOSSARY
TONPA
[Leorio gulps]
[Lippo over speaker]
Gentlemen, let me explain.
You've probably already noticed
that some of the prisoners of Trick Tower
are standing before you.
They're prisoners?
[Lippo] Not just prisoners.
The Hunter Exam Committee has also
officially hired them on as examiners.
In this phase, you'll be fighting
against all five of them.
The fights will be one-on-one,
with each person fighting only once.
Use any style you like.
There will be no draws.
To be declared the victor,
your opponent must admit defeat.
You can decide which of you will be
the first contender.
And this is majority rule,
which means you have to secure three wins
in order to pass.
The rules are simple.
[sighs] I'm getting real tired of this.
Meh, seems pretty straightforward to me.
Hmm, well, the fights themselves
will be anything but.
For every hour
the prisoners keep you occupied here,
their sentences will be reduced
by one year.
In other words, their goal in this phase
is to literally buy time.
I understand. We're on the clock,
and if we don't reach the goal
of getting out of here in 72 hours,
we fail.
So, as you're fighting, remember:
time is of the essence.
Bendot- Robber and murderer
Sentenced to 199 years in prison
Okay, I'm fighting whoever's first.
Now, who's it gonna be?
Now what?
He said to fight however we want,
so I'm guess that pretty much means
anything goes.
Everybody, be careful.
No telling what they'll try to pull.
Without knowing what's up their sleeves,
there's far too much at stake.
-Given that, I'll--
-[Tonpa] No, I'll go!
Mr. Tonpa?
I'll be the guinea pig; see if I can
figure out what they're up to.
Consider it an apology for earlier.
Hold on, you're serious?
Sure.
You guys don't trust me yet, and I know
I've given you plenty of reasons not to.
If the score ends up being two to two,
who do you want going in there
to break the tie? 'Cause it ain't me!
That actually makes sense.
Good, so it's settled then.
Tonpa, so you're...
Hmm.
Well, that was a surprise.
Never thought he'd volunteer.
He didn't really strike me
as the guinea pig type.
Do you guys think he'll be okay?
Now then, let's determine
the method of combat.
My choice would be a battle to the death.
-[Tonpa gasps]
-A death match?
They're gonna fight 'til one of them dies?
This is bad.
Don't let him provoke you, Tonpa!
What do you say?
I accept.
To the death, then! Let's go!
-[all gasp]
-Seriously?
You're a brave man, I'll give you that.
[all grunt]
[grunting]
T-- Tonpa!
Now, begin!
[roaring]
I give up!
Huh?
What?
Did he just say that he gives up?
Uh, maybe he meant "give me a sec"?
[prisoner] What did you just say?
I said I admit defeat.
That means you win, right?
So, I give up. I lose! [laughs]
Wha-- wha-- what!
[prisoner chuckles]
All right.
Guess the first round goes to me, then!
If we win another two rounds, that's it.
You all fail the exam.
You can't advance and you can't turn back.
You'll be stuck here
for the next 72 hours,
until the exam is over.
And if that happens,
our sentences will be reduced
by a grand total of 72 years.
[cackles]
Oh, man, am I embarrassed!
He looked a hell of a lot tougher
when I got up close.
Bastard!
I knew we shouldn't have trusted you.
All you're good for is
sabotaging the other applicants!
You're just a worthless piece of garbage!
It took you long enough.
That's what I do every year,
and I'll keep doing it
for as long as I can.
Wait, say what?
[Tonpa] I don't care about passing
the Hunter Exam.
I'm in it for the thrills.
Sorry to disappoint.
-[Leorio] The thrills?
-[Tonpa] That's right.
The exam is a proving ground,
designed to crush the dreams
of the young and over-confident.
And that moment when hope and ambition
give way to absolute despair...
[chuckles] I get a kick out of that.
The joy I feel is just exquisite.
Especially when I'm the one
actively shattering the newbies' dreams.
There's nothing like that rush.
I've no desire to be a Hunter.
Doesn't really interest me.
And I've already had enough fun
for this year.
Besides, I usually stop
at this point anyway.
-Bastard!
-Leorio, stop!
Why?
We're wasting time fighting each other.
That's exactly what they want.
[Leorio grunts]
Yeah, but if their goal was
to kill as much time as possible,
then the move the old man made
was actually the right one.
[Tonpa] Huh?
[Killua] That bald guy looks ex-military,
probably a mercenary.
If you'd fought with him,
he'd have started by crushing your larynx.
Pretty hard to give up
if you can't even talk.
Then he'd have tortured you, without
killing you, for as long as he liked.
Yep, I considered that possibility.
You look sick, old man.
Well, so much for that plan, I guess.
I was gonna take my sweet time
torturing the guy until the clock ran out.
[Sedokan]
Don't worry. Everything will be fine.
Sedokan -Serial bomber
Sentenced to 149 years in prison
If we defeat two of the next four,
then victory will be ours.
All right. We need to win three rounds.
It's the only way we'll be able
to advance.
So, who wants to go next?
Me! I'll give it a try.
-Are you sure?
-Yeah.
[Killua] Well, the next opponent
doesn’t look too strong.
I wouldn’t let my guard down
if I were you.
He’s still a hardened criminal.
No telling what he’s capable of.
Yeah, I'll be careful.
[narrator] Tonpa’s actions have placed Gon
and his friends at a serious disadvantage.
Their next opponent is Sedokan.
As for what exactly he plans to do
in this match, it’s anybody’s guess.
At the start of the Third Phase
of the Hunter Exam,
there were 40 applicants.
And now, with one eliminated,
only 39 remain.
[theme music plays]
[Gon] Next time,
"Beware of Prisoners".
Oh, and watch your back, okay?
[Kurapika]
Be careful when you're out late.